<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on S.M. Oliva</title>
    <link>https://smoliva.blog/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on S.M. Oliva</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://smoliva.blog/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Catherine the Great--The Progressive Russian Autocrat?</title>
      <link>https://smoliva.blog/post/catherine-the-great/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smoliva.blog/post/catherine-the-great/</guid>
      <description>While perusing the offerings from my local library online, a biography of Catherine the Great&amp;ndash;the former Empress Catherine II of Russia&amp;ndash;caught my eye. I knew next-to-nothing about Catherine. to be honest, I only recognized the name because I had played her as a character a few times in Sid Meier&amp;rsquo;s Civilization IV. But I always enjoy a good biography, so I decided to rent and read this particular book, Catherine the Great: Portrait of a Woman by Robert K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging with Hugo, Part 3</title>
      <link>https://smoliva.blog/post/blogging-with-hugo-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smoliva.blog/post/blogging-with-hugo-3/</guid>
      <description>My last post detailed the process of setting up the virtual private server (VPS) to host this blog. In this final post, I&amp;rsquo;ll go into the mechanics of actually developing the blog using Hugo.
If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar with Hugo, it is software written in the Go language to function as a static website generator. Static means the entire website is generated at once, as opposed to a dynamic content management system like WordPress, which builds a particular page upon request from a database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging with Hugo, Part 2</title>
      <link>https://smoliva.blog/post/blogging-with-hugo-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smoliva.blog/post/blogging-with-hugo-2/</guid>
      <description>In Part 1, I explained my decision to go with Hover for domain registation and Linode for the virtual private server (VPS) I use for this blog. Now, I&amp;rsquo;ll briefly review the process of setting up the VPS and getting it to work with my domain.
Obviously, I relied principally on documentation prepared by others. Specifically, I used how-tos published by both Linode and one of its competitors, Digital Ocean. I actually find the Digital Ocean documentation a bit easier to read and follow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging with Hugo, Part 1</title>
      <link>https://smoliva.blog/post/blogging-with-hugo-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smoliva.blog/post/blogging-with-hugo-1/</guid>
      <description>In developing my new blog, I opted to build a static website using Hugo and other open source software tools, as opposed to using an all-in-one commercial service like Squarespace or WordPress. There are certain advantages to this DIY approach, as well as drawbacks. So in this series of posts, I&amp;rsquo;ll walk through my thought process in deciding to use Hugo and explain the steps I took in building this blog &amp;ldquo;from scratch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Desktop Linux in 2021</title>
      <link>https://smoliva.blog/post/using-desktop-linux-in-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smoliva.blog/post/using-desktop-linux-in-2021/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago, I purchased an iPad. This is my first Apple device in awhile, so I decided to check and see if my Apple ID still worked. It did, albeit after going through the process of resetting my long-forgotten password.
To my slight surprise, this was the first time I&amp;rsquo;d used my Apple ID since 2012. That was the year I moved away from OS X to Linux as my everyday operating system.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
